The first end of the century in 100 years
Сотня лет прошла, и век подошёл к концу...
When told to cry, I laughed instead
Скажет кто-то слёзы лить? Рассмеюсь в ответ!
The first end of the century in a long, long time
Много лет прошло, и век подошёл к концу...
We're leaping into a wide open world
Безграничный мир нас ждёт — так бежим скорей!
The things I tried to understand as a child
С детства в толк не мог я взять, вещей различных я не понимал...
remain a mystery even as an adult
И даже в жизни взрослой... загадкою остались!
I'm neither a hotshot nor especially great
Я, может, и не герой, не так хорош я собой,
All I understand is the pounding of my heart
и понимаю я лишь, как сердце быстро бьётся!
It's neither an answer nor the truth
Ответ ещё не нашёл и истину не обрёл...
All I have faith in is the pounding of my heart
Верю я лишь в то, что сердце быстро бьётся.
That and nothing else
Лишь в то, что сердце бьётся.
The Threatening Monthly Presents.
«Ежемесячные подарки с угрозами».
You know Shinichi Kudo, Ran?!
Ран, так ты знаешь Синъити Кудо?!
Eh? Well, yeah...
А? Ну да...
Awesome!
Круто!
I can't believe you know the super-famous high school detective!
Надо же, знаешь супер известного старшеклассника-детектива!
He wouldn't happen to be your boyfriend, would he?
А вы, случайно, с ним не встречаетесь?
No! Nothing of the sort!
Вовсе нет! С чего ты взял?!
Why are you reacting the same way?
А ты почему так реагируешь?
No, it's just that--
Ну, понимаешь...
He's your boyfriend, isn't he?!
Так он твой парень?
Oh, well, you see...
Да нет, послушайте...
I can't really answer that!
Хватит о таком спрашивать!
We're home!
Мы вернулись!
Come to think of it, what could Shinichi be doing?
Кстати говоря, где сейчас Синъити?
It's been a while since I last heard anything from him...
Давненько он не звонил...
The case he's working on has probably hit a hard spot!
Наверняка у него сейчас сложное дело!
But normally he solves all of his cases without any problems at all...
Но обычно он решает все дела без проблем...
Do you think that maybe he's...
Неужели он...
...gotten worse at being a detective?
потерял хватку?
Coming!
Иду!
What's going on?
Что происходит?
I'm so sorry, little boy!
Прости, мальчик!
Are you all right?
Ты цел?
Yeah...
Да...
My name is Ogawa.
Меня зовут Огава.
Since about 2 years ago,
Уже на протяжении двух лет
someone has been sending me toys and money every month.
мне каждый месяц отправляют деньги и игрушки.
It's kind of creepy
Меня пугает,
because the sender's name and address are always made-up.
что имя и адрес отправителя вымышленные.
Toys and money, huh?
Игрушки и деньги?
Do you have any children?
А у вас есть дети?
Yes. A 5-year old son named Yuta.
Да. Пятилетний сын Юта.
Exactly how much money have they been sending?
И сколько денег вам присылали?
1 million yen each month.
Миллион иен каждый месяц.
It will total 25 million this month!
Набралось уже двадцать пять миллионов!
25 million?!
Двадцать пять миллионов?!
Yuta loves the fact that new toys come every month,
Юте нравится, что присылают игрушки,
but being sent money is too creepy for me so I haven't touched any of it.
но меня пугают деньги, и я их не трогал.
If that's the case, I wouldn't mind holding on to the money for you!
В таком случае, я не против их придержать!
Dad!
Папа!
I was just kidding!
Да я пошутил.
Do you have any ideas who it could be?
У вас есть предположения, от кого это?
No.
Нет.
Are you sure it isn't one of your patients?
Уверены, что это не один из пациентов?
Patients?
Пациентов?
You're a surgeon, aren't you?
Вы ведь хирург?
I am...
Ну да...
Then it wouldn't be strange for one of the patients you saved
Вполне естественно, что один из пациентов
to send all this to you in appreciation for your help, would it?
хочет отблагодарить вас за труды.
No...
Нет...
Huh? I don't remember mentioning that I was a surgeon...
Что? Я ведь вроде не говорил, кем работаю...
How did you know that, Conan-kun?!
И как ты догадался, Конан?
It was his index fingers.
По его указательным пальцам.
My fingers?
По пальцам?
You have diagonal marks on your fingers, right?
У вас диагональные отметины на пальцах.
When performing operations,
Во время операций
surgeons use both index fingers to sew tight sutures.
хирурги при зашивании используют указательные пальцы.
Over time, it causes diagonal marks to appear on their index fingers!
Из-за этого со временем появляются такие отметины!
Is he right?!
Так это правда?
Yes...
Да...
In fact, I performed a surgery just this very morning.
Я оперировал ещё утром.
Excellent work, my lad!
И как ты догадался, мальчик!
This kid knows all sorts of weird stuff...
Этот малец знает всякие странности...
But that was amazing, Conan-kun!
Это так здорово, Конан!
Almost like...
Почти как...
You're in a gymnastics club, aren't you?
Вы ведь занимаетесь гимнастикой?
Only people who train on the horizontal bar ever get this many blisters.
Так много мозолей только у тех, кто занимается на перекладине.
Almost like Shinichi...
Прямо как Синъити...
H-He couldn't be...
Неужели он...
He couldn't be.
Быть не может.
This came today.
Это пришло сегодня.
There doesn't seem to be anything strange besides the money...
Помимо денег не вижу ничего странного...
No! Normally it's a much larger package with both toys and money in it!
Нет. Обычно игрушки с деньгами приходят в больших коробках.
This is the first time it's been like this...
И именно сегодня...
A letter.
Письмо.
I have finished paying the 25 million yen. I will be coming to get what is mine.
Я закончил выплату двадцати пяти миллионов. А теперь я заберу своё.
What exactly does this mean?
И что это значит?
Your guess is as good as mine.
Я и сам не понимаю.
Hey, why don't these have those line patterns on them?
А почему тут нет отметин?
Line patterns?
Отметин?
There's one on that.
Например, здесь.
Oh, you mean a barcode.
А, ты про штрих-код.
That is strange.
И правда, странно.
There aren't any on any of these things!
На остальном такого нет!
They don't sell these toys in stores anymore...
Эти игрушки уже не продаются...
And it looks like some have been damaged...
А некоторые даже повреждены...
Come to think of it, ever since the toys started coming in,
Кстати, пока приходили игрушки,
some of them were worn out, and others were completely broken.
некоторые оказались потрёпаны, а другие сломаны.
In other words, they've either been sending used toys
То есть вам отправляли либо старые,
or toys that they had purchased quite a while ago.
либо давно купленные игрушки.
Along with the large sums of money!
Ещё и с большими суммами!
But why?!
Но почему же?
Most likely...
Скорее всего...
...it's just an ordinary prank!
это был розыгрыш!
A prank?
Розыгрыш?
Yup, no doubt about it.
Да, сомнений нет.
No, it's too complicated for a simple prank.
Нет, для розыгрыша слишком сложно.
And sending all that money for no reason would be pointless...
Такие суммы не отправляют без причины...
And then there's that letter...
Ещё и письмо...
You have such excellent powers of deduction, Mori-san!
Какая восхитительная дедукция, Мори!
That was nothing at all.
Ну что вы, не стоит.
No! Dad didn't figure any of those things out!
Нет! Это не папины выводы.
It was all because of Conan-kun!
Всё из-за Конана!
He couldn't be...
Неужели...
He couldn't be!
Быть не может! Он...
So this letter is the only clue as to who the sender is...
Единственная зацепка — это письмо...
Say, do you think the sender could be trying to buy something
А вам не кажется, что отправитель пытался что-то
from Ogawa-san?
купить у Огавы?
Depending on how you interpret it, it could mean something like that.
Вполне возможно, что речь идёт об этом.
Now that you mention it...
Если так задуматься...
There is a painting in the hospital that my grandfather left me.
В больнице есть картина, которую мне оставил дед.
I'm pretty sure they said that it was worth about 20 million yen...
Кажется, она стоит около двадцати миллионов иен...
That's it!
Вот оно что!
The sender must want to buy that painting from you!
Возможно, отправителю нужна эта картина!
Let's all go to the hospital and have a look at the painting!
Пойдём в больницу и посмотрим!
We may find more details!
Что-то может проясниться.
Okay! Let's go!
Так, вперёд.
Beika Hospital
Больница Бэйка
This certainly is a large hospital!
Какая большая больница!
I, too, was surprised when I first came here 3 years ago.
Я и сам был удивлён, когда начал здесь работать.
I was transferred here from a small rural hospital, you see...
Понимаете, я перевёлся из маленькой больницы...
Ogawa-sensei. Another one of these.
Доктор Огава. Вам снова прислали подарок.
Another one this year, huh?
И в этом году?
Morning glories? With the weather as cold as it is?
Утренняя слава? В такую-то погоду?
I can only assume that the person has been growing them in a greenhouse.
Вероятно, эти цветы выращивались в оранжерее.
Wait, they've been sending these too?
Вам и такое отправляли?
Yes, the same person has been sending these as well.
Да, я получаю их каждый год.
But the flowers only come once a year.
Но цветы присылают лишь один раз.
On today, February 19th.
И всегда девятнадцатого февраля.
Sending flowers must mean the sender is female...
Скорее всего, цветы отправляет женщина...
The phrase associated with morning glories is "a short-lived love."
А на языке цветов они означают «мимолётную любовь».
Don't tell me you did something with another woman 2 years ago...
Неужели у вас была интрижка два года назад...
Nothing of the sort!
Ничего подобного!
Then could it be your son's birthday or something?
А когда день рождения у сына?
Yuta's birthday is in December.
Юта родился в декабре.
If it's okay with him,
Если доктор Огава не против,
why don't we have a look at Ogawa-sensei's medical records?
посмотрим записи с его операций?
There might be a patient who has something to do with February 19th!
Возможно, это связано с пациентом с девятнадцатого февраля!
That's right.
Точно.
May we have a look?
Можно нам взглянуть?
I'm not allowed to show the records to other people...
Нельзя показывать их посторонним...
Can't we bend the rules just this once?
Может, разок всё же можно?
Very well. I suppose I have no other choice.
Хорошо. Похоже, выбора нет.
Sorry to bother you like this!
Простите уж!
Well, here are all of my patients' records for the past 3 years.
Вот записи о моих пациентах за последние три года.
And there's nobody in here who might want that painting?
И никто точно не спрашивал про вашу картину?
No.
Нет.
Say, would you like to see the painting for yourself?
Если хотите, можете взглянуть.
Sure.
Хорошо.
It's hanging in the patients' waiting room.
Она висит в зоне ожидания.
You're not coming, Conan-kun?
А ты не пойдёшь, Конан?
I'll wait here!
Я здесь подожду!
Ok!
Ага!
The painting is quite popular among many of the patients too!
Эта картина пользуется популярностью у пациентов.
Conan-kun! Something's not right!
Конан! Что-то явно не так!
He's acting too strangely for an ordinary grade school student!
Он слишком странный для обычного младшеклассника!
Yeah! Back then, too!
Точно! И в тот раз тоже...
So this dog barks at all strangers then?
Эта собака ведь лает на посторонних?
And that other time too!
И в тот раз...
How did you know this was a lighter if you've never been here before?
И как вы догадались, если не были здесь раньше?
It was almost like Shinichi was giving suggestions!
Строил предположения как Синъити!
Yeah!
Точно!
The day Shinichi disappeared...
В день, когда исчез Синъити...
...Conan-kun showed up, in his place, almost...
вдруг объявился Конан...
I'll have to make sure!
Нужно это проверить...
Here goes!
Так!
What're you doing?!
Эй!
You shouldn't be reading people's records without permission!
Нельзя без спроса читать чужие заметки.
R-Ran!
Р-Ран!
Did you find anything?
Что-нибудь нашёл?
Yeah, sort of.
Ну, вроде того.
He said earlier that the flowers are sent to the hospital once a year, right?
Доктор ведь сказал, что цветы отправляют раз в год?
That makes me think that it was a former patient here.
Значит, они, скорее всего, от бывшего пациента.
It was 2 years ago when he started receiving the toys and the money,
Раз он начал получать игрушки и деньги да года назад,
so that narrows it down to patients who were here
можно сузить поиски до людей,
during Ogawa-san's first year at this hospital.
которые были у него в первый год.
Among them, there are 8 people
Среди них восемь человек,
who have something to do with February 19th.
связанных с девятнадцатым.
People whose surgeries were successful on that day,
Те, кто был успешно прооперирован,
Sending flowers most likely means the person is grateful to him,
Цветы наверняка выражают благодарность, но кое-что
The morning glories grown with care in a greenhouse, and that letter...
Заботливо выращенная утренняя слава, то письмо...
It's amazing that you could figure that much out!
И как ты до всего догадался!
Great work, Shinichi!
Молодец, Синъити!
It was nothing--
Пустяки...
I knew it!
Так и знала!
You are Shinichi!
Ты и есть Синъити!
W-What are you talking about, Ran?
О-о чём это ты, Ран?
My name's Conan! Conan!
Меня же зовут Конан!
Stop playing around!
Хватит так шутить!
Not good! She's found me out!
Плохо дело, меня раскусили!
If word gets out that I'm actually Shinichi Kudo,
Если кто-то узнает, что я Синъити Кудо,
they'll come back to kill me!
они обязательно придут за мной!
And if that happens,
В таком случае,
they might go after Ran and the others as well!
Ран и остальные тоже будут в опасности!
I have to fool her somehow!
Нужно её обдурить!
Wow! A Game Man! And Yaiba's Great Adventure!
Ого! Гейммен! И приключения Яйбы!
Go Yaiba! Beat up Onimaru!
Вперёд, Яйба! Давай, побей Онимару!
This is fun!
Так весело!
I think he's faking! It's too suspicious!
Явно притворяется! Так ещё подозрительнее.
Conan-kun must really be Shinichi...
Конан наверняка и есть Синъити...
But this sort of thing doesn't happen...
Но такого же не бывает...
This isn't a science fiction movie, after all...
Это не научно-фантастический фильм...
Wait a minute!
Погодите!
If he really is, then...
Если так и есть, то...
Say, Conan-kun.
Слушай, Конан...
Is there anyone you like?
А тебе кто-то нравится?
I have someone I really like!
А у меня есть любимый человек!
Don't tell me it's that Shinichi boy you were looking for earlier?
Неужели тот самый братик Синъити, которого ты искала?
That's right!
Так и есть!
He's always been kind of a tease since he was a kid,
Он всегда был врединой,
and he's always been so full of himself and a big mystery geek,
а ещё он детективный чудик,
but he's also courageous, cool, and dependable!
но зато он храбрый, крутой и надёжный, хоть и слишком зазнаётся!
I really like Shinichi a lot!
Мне очень нравится Синъити!
Oh no! Game over!
Вот блин, проиграл.
Hey, you wanna try, Ran?
Хочешь тоже сыграть, Ран?
You like this sort of thing, don't you?
Тебе же такое нравится?
L-Like...
Н-нравится...
I do not! Don't get the wrong idea!
Вовсе нет! Нечего тут придумывать!
You don't? I'll keep playing then...
Правда? Тогда продолжу играть...
Tomoya Ogino?
Томоя Огино?
Huh? Ogawa-san said his son was named Yuta...
Что? Кажется, сына Огавы зовут Юта...
Normally you enter your own name or the name of a character you like...
Обычно вводят либо имя персонажа, либо своё...
Wait. Tomoya Ogino.
Стойте, Томоя Огино.
Where have I seen this name before?
Где я уже видел это имя?
That's it!
Точно!
Here it is!
Вот оно!
Tomoya Ogino, 5 years old.
Томоя Огино, пять лет.
He died after Ogawa-san operated on him.
Умер после операции доктора Огавы.
Three years ago, on February 19th!
Три года назад, девятнадцатого февраля!
I have finished paying the 25 million yen. I will be coming to get what is mine.
Я закончил выплату двадцати пяти миллионов. А теперь я заберу своё.
The letter couldn't mean what I think it does!
Неужели речь об этом!..
Ran! Bring Mr. Ogawa here right away!
Ран! Быстро приведи сюда доктора Огаву!
Hurry! There's no time!
Скорее! У нас нет времени!
It has to be!
Я права.
That tone, his mannerisms, his deductions...
Этот голос, поведение, дедукция...
They're all exactly like Shinichi's! No question about it!
Он вылитый Синъити, в этом я уверена!
Did you really find out who the sender is?!
Ты выяснил, кто был отправителем?!
I think it might be the parents of Tomoya Ogino-kun here!
Думаю, это были родители Томои Огино.
Tomoya Ogino?
Томои Огино?
The one who died of appendicitis three years ago!
Он умер от аппендицита три года назад.
People can die from appendicitis?
От аппендицита можно умереть?
Yes. If it's not detected early enough...
Да. Если вовремя не определить...
It was already too late for him when they brought him in to the hospital...
Когда его привезли в больницу, было уже поздно.
The boy's father absolutely would not listen to me, however...
Его отец, правда, и слышать ничего не хотел...
But why would he send you presents if the operation wasn't successful?
И зачем отправлять подарки, если операция не успешна?
They're neither presents nor used goods!
Это далеко не подержанные подарки!
They're the belongings of the late Tomoya Ogino, who died 3 years ago!
Всё это вещи Томои Огино, умершего три года назад!
In other words, he's been sending all of his son's keepsakes!
То есть он отправлял вещи своего сына!
Sending them out of hatred!
И всё это из ненависти.
The flowers are delivered to the hospital every February 19th
А цветы отправлялись на каждую
because it's the anniversary of his son's death!
годовщину смерти сына!
And that letter means that he's going to take the life of Ogawa-san's son
А письмо означает, что он отнимет жизнь сына Огавы
on the exact same day!
за своего сына!
What?!
Что?!
Where's your son right now?!
Где сейчас ваш сын?!
My wife should be on her way to pick him up at school!
Жена поехала за ним в школу.
Contact her at once!
Немедленно ей позвоните!
Someone already picked him up?!
Кто-то уже забрал его?!
They told me his father had already picked him up!
Сказали, что его уже забрал отец!
It wasn't you?!
Так это был не ты?!
T-This can't be happening...
Б-быть не может...
This is bad!
Плохо дело!
If we don't find them soon, Yuta-kun's a goner!
Если вскоре их не найдём, Юту убьют!
Where's the school?!
Где школа?!
It isn't very far from here...
Отсюда недалеко...
Then they're still nearby!
Значит, они рядом!
Conan-kun!
Конан!
Look, little boy.
Вот, мальчик.
I have a present for you!
У меня тут подарочек!
Yay!
Ура!
Thank you, Mister!
Спасибо вам, дядя!
Hey, are you really gonna take me to a fun place after this?
А вы правда отведёте меня веселиться?
Sure. I'll take you there soon.
Конечно же отведу.
To where Tomoya is.
Прямо к Томое.
Where?! Where are they?!
Где? Где же они?!
Tomoya!
Томоя!
It must have been lonely all by yourself!
Наверное, тебе было одиноко...
I'll bring you a friend soon!
Скоро у тебя появится друг.
Right now, in fact!
Прямо сейчас.
That's Yuta!
Это же Юта!
What?!
Что?!
Not good!
Плохо дело.
Here goes! Try this on for size!
Ну вот, давай!
Go!
Вперёд!
Did Conan-kun do that just now?!
Это был Конан?
Yuta!
Юта!
Daddy!
Папа!
Stop right there!
А ну стоять!
Move and you know what'll happen!
А не то вы знаете, что случится!
Ogino-san! So it was you!
Огино! Так это были вы!
That's right! It was me!
Именно! Это был я!
I'm the father of Tomoya Ogino,
Я отец Томои Огино,
who you killed 3 years ago when you messed up his operation!
которого вы убили три года назад!
It wasn't my fault!
Я был не виноват!
It was already too late when they carried him--
Было уже слишком поздно...
Shut up! As if you would understand the feelings of a father
Молчать! Вам ни за что не понять чувства отца,
whose son was murdered just after he turned 5!
чьего пятилетнего сына убили!
All I had left were his remains and the 25 million in insurance money!
Остались лишь его труп и страховка в двадцать пять миллионов!
So that's why you sent all that money...
Вот почему вы отправили эти деньги...
That's right.
Именно.
The money, his toys, and the morning glories that he loved so much!
Деньги, игрушки и его любимые цветы, утренняя слава!
It was with my hatred that I sent them all to you!
Я хотел выразить свою ненависть!
Now it's your turn to feel what it's like to lose your own son!
Ваш черёд на своей шкуре ощутить, что значит потерять сына.
Please! Don't hurt my son!
Прошу, не трогайте его!
Kill me instead!
Лучше убейте меня!
Just let my son go!
Только сына пощадите!
Oh! So you were the one who sent the toys!
Вот как! Так это вы отправляли игрушки!
Thank you, Mister!
Спасибо вам, дядя!
I always take good care of them all!
Я очень аккуратно с ними обращался!
T-Tomoya!
Т-Томоя!
Tomoya...
Томоя...
What's wrong, Mister?
Что такое, дядя?
Did Daddy and the others say something bad to you?
Папа сказал вам что-то плохое?
No, little boy.
Нет, малыш.
I was the bad one.
Это я здесь плохой.
I knew.
Я ведь понимал.
I knew from the very start that it wasn't his fault.
Понимал, что он здесь ни при чём.
But I had to fool myself into thinking it was, or else I...
Но я убеждал себя в обратном, чтобы...
I'm sorry, little boy! I'm so sorry!
Прости, мальчик! Мне так жаль!
Ran. Call the police.
Ран. Вызови полицию.
Wait! Please don't get the police involved!
Постойте! Не вовлекайте полицию.
But he just tried to kill your son.
Он ведь пытался убить вашего сына.
It's all right.
Всё хорошо.
I see...
Ладно...
Ogino-san. I know exactly how you feel.
Огино. Я прекрасно вас понимаю.
After all, I am a father before I'm a doctor.
Я ведь не только доктор, но и отец.
How lucky it was that it didn't turn into a serious incident.
Повезло, что всё обошлось.
But why did he send the money and toys for 2 whole years?
Но почему он целых два года отправлял игрушки и деньги?
He was probably waiting for Yuta-kun to turn 5 first.
Наверняка ждал, пока Юте не исполнится пять.
The same age that Tomoya-kun was when he died 3 years ago...
Ждал возраста, в котором три года назад умер Томоя...
Excellent deduction skills you have there.
Какая гениальная догадка.
But I'm just a kid so I don't really know for sure!
Я просто ребёнок, так что не уверен!
I just remembered something I have to do!
У меня появилось дело!
Go on home without me!
Идите без меня!
What's with him?
Что с ним такое?
Just my imagination
Лишь в воображении
Playing with threads around my finger while drinking lukewarm tea
игриво нити накрутил уже на пальцы, чай остывший давно до сих пор попиваю!
Let's walk lightly to the bossa nova rhythm
В ритме босса-нова шагаем, трудности преодолеваем,
The puzzle pieces are in my hands
И частички пазла уже у нас в руках!
That's right...
Вот так-так-так-так...
I was in the same place last week but with different clothes
Я в другой одежде на прошлой неделе... уже приходил сюда!
Step by step, there's no reason to be anxious
Шаг за шагом, нет причины излишне спешить!
I'm home!
Я вернулся!
Huh? Where's your dad?
А где твой папа?
He went drinking.
Ушёл выпить.
You must be hungry. I'll make you something.
Ты наверняка голодный. Приготовлю что-нибудь.
Okay!
Ага.
Oh, yeah!
Точно!
I hear our shop teacher Kishida-sensei is getting married!
Говорят, наш трудовик Кисида женится!
That gorilla?
Та горилла?
How do you know about my high school teacher?
И откуда ты знаешь, как он выглядит?
No, uh, you're always talking about how he's a gorilla!
Ну, ты же всегда его так называла.
Liar!
Не ври мне!
I couldn't believe it at first, but I guess you really are Shinichi!
Поначалу это казалось нелепым, но ты и правда Синъити!
No, I'm...
Нет, я...
Just confess already! Shinichi!
А ну признавайся, Синъити!
T-The phone...
Т-телефон...
Let it ring!
Пусть звонит.
B-But...
Н-но...
Alright! I'll pick it up!
Да хватит, сейчас возьму!
Yeah, this is the Mori Detective--
Да, детективное агентство...
Hey, Ran!
Привет, Ран!
It's been a while!
Давно не виделись!
S-Shinichi?
С-Синъити?
No way! You're right--
Да ладно! Ты же...
Hey, now. Have you already forgotten the sound of my voice?
Ты что, совсем позабыла мой голос?
How cruel!
Жестокая ты.
Darn that Shinichi!
Чёртов Синъити!
Please, Professor Agasa! I think Ran's on to me!
Прошу, профессор Агата! Ран меня подозревает!
Call her using my voice!
Позвони ей от моего лица!
He shouldn't have made her worry so much like that!
Не стоит так сильно её волновать.
Hey, Ran.
Эй, Ран.
Are you there, Ran?
Ты хоть слушаешь, Ран?
I'm so stupid! I think I misunderstood things!
Какая я глупышка! Что-то я явно напутала.
No, it's nothing.
Да так, пустяки.
Say, Shinichi. Have you started using words that old men use?
Слушай, Синъити. Что у тебя за стариковские обороты?
You're a life-saver.
Прямо спас.
There are so many beautiful paintings!
Как много красивых картин!
I'm so glad we came!
Не зря мы пришли.
Look at this! The colors are lovely!
Взгляните, такие цвета.
What's with that expression?!
Что за выражение?
What's on the card that he's so shocked about?!
Что его так сильно удивило?
On the next Conan--
Далее в «Конане»:
The Murder of the Art Museum Owner.
«Убийство владельца художественной галереи».
Next Conan's Hint:
Следующая зацепка Конана:
Ball Pen Observation.
Внимание на шариковую ручку.
Don't miss the next episode
До следующей серии
If you don't watch the next episode, you'll fall behind!
В следующий раз смотрите в оба!